carnival.com 2015-06-27

# Privacy Policy | Legal | Carnival Cruise Lines

This website and any mobile application linked to this privacy policy (collectively the “Sites”) is owned and operated by Carnival Cruise Lines, a division of Carnival Corporation ("Carnival"). Carnival is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy and helping you make the most of your time on the Internet within a trusted environment. The Carnival Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) applies to the Sites and governs the data collection, usage and services available on the Sites. This Privacy Policy discloses how we collect, protect, use and share information gathered about you on our Sites. If you use our Sites you explicitly agree to the terms and conditions of the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of your use. We hope that this disclosure will help increase your confidence in our Sites and enhance your experience on the Internet. Please read our Privacy Policy to understand:

**Information We Collect**  
You can visit our Sites without divulging any personally identifiable information including your email address. Our Sites do not collect personally identifiable information about individuals except when such individuals specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis, such as when registering at our website, accessing certain functions of our mobile application or accessing our online cruise booking application. Carnival uses such information collected primarily to provide better customer service to you, to improve and customize the content you see, to provide the products, services or membership benefits you request, and to contact you about special promotions and new products.

**Site Use Information**  
Our web servers collect the IP addresses and domain names of visitors to our site. Our mobile application may automatically collect your mobile device identification. This information may be aggregated to measure the number of visits, average time spent on the site, features accessed, pages viewed, etc. Carnival may use this information to measure the use of our Sites and to improve the content we offer. We may share with third parties this experiential information or other data which does not personally identify visitors to our Sites. This might include tour or ship preferences of all visitors to our Sites, for example.

**Use of Cookies**

Our website uses "cookies" to help personalize your online experience, such as recognizing your name when you revisit, as well as to assist us in marketing and advertising. A cookie is a text file that is anonymously placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies placed when you visit our site do not personally identify you, but they do allow us to monitor certain statistics which help us improve our services, such as how many site visitors view certain pages on our website or receive our advertisements when visiting other websites. Some cookies are temporary and expire and automatically erased when you close your browser window.  Other cookies (persistent cookies) have an expiration date in the distant future and remain in your browser until they expire or you manually delete them. We use persistent cookies to better understand usage patterns so we can improve the site for our customers, and to remember you and your preferences when you return to the Sites.

Third party cookies:  We permit limited third parties to place cookies through the Sites to provide us with better insights into the use of the Sites or user demographics or to provide relevant advertising to you.  These third parties may collect information about a consumer’s online activities over time and across different websites when he or she uses our website.

You also have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of our website or have some of our services, such as planning a cruise, making a reservation, or being automatically recognized as a registered user, function properly.

We do not use technology that recognizes a “do-not-track signal from your web browser.  This technology allows us to exclude you from any analytics that collect information about your online activities over time and across third party websites 

**Information You Provide to Us**

You are not required to register in order to access our website or to download our mobile application. If you send us an email, participate in one of our blogs or forums, or register on our Sites we may collect information about you. Certain portions of our Sites are restricted to registered users or passengers with confirmed bookings. Any information you provide is purely voluntary.

There are several areas on the site where you may provide personal information or will be required to register to obtain access to certain online services not available to anonymous visitors. These include My Profile, Sign in/Register, My Cruise Manager, Online Check-in, Book Now, Shore Excursions, Fun Job and Contact Us. You may apply for employment online through our site. Travel agents may register with Carnival through the GoCCL.com site linked from our website.  Mobile application users are required to provide identity information in order to use certain features of the application, such as accessing your Sail & Sign account or communicate with other passengers.

When you register on our Sites, you will be required to provide your first name, last name, email address and to select a password to be used to access your information. To access My Cruise Manager or your Sail & Sign account, you may be required to use your Login Information and a valid booking number obtained from Carnival. If you want to book travel or other services through our Sites, you may be required to register in advance in order to obtain access. 

When you register we collect information which may include your name, address, gender, birth date, email address, telephone number, special occasion dates, vacation and dietary preferences, health requirements, and passport and credit card information (cardholder name, card number and expiration date) as well as emergency contact information (the name, address and telephone number of someone not traveling with you who we can contact in case of an emergency. ("Profile Information"). 

Information collected in My Cruise Manager may include Profile Information for yourself and those traveling with you. By providing us with the Profile Information of any third party, you are agreeing and acknowledging that you have the express right and authority to do so on their behalf.  Each person whose Profile Information is linked to the same My Cruise Manager account agrees that their information may be accessible to all others included in that My Cruise Manager account.

If you make purchases through our Sites we will collect your contact information including your phone number and email address, your credit card billing information and information about the person receiving the product purchased.  We use this information to complete your purchase and for our general commercial purposes.  For your security we do not store your credit card number,

Information collected through the Fun Job online application may include name, address, telephone and fax numbers, email address, age, education history, military service, immigration status and employment history. Job applicants may choose to provide this information by mail or fax instead of through the site. 

Passengers are not required to use Online Check-in to submit information before they begin their cruise; the same information, which is required before boarding, can be provided over the telephone by calling 1-888-CARNIVAL or can be provided at the point of embarkation. Using Online Check-in will speed up your boarding process because information is submitted in advance. This information may be shared with governmental agencies including Customs or the Department of Homeland Security, with medical staff and with Carnival personnel. Carnival is required to share certain passenger information with local government agencies depending on clearance procedures at the port of call. We may keep your credit card and passport information on file and on our servers to enable you to make purchases on board more easily, to facilitate your boarding procedure and other transactions between us, and to resolve disputes as may arise between us and you.

Our mobile application provides features that require you to submit information in order for the feature to function this information will be used by Carnival for our general commercial purposes.

 From time to time we may offer promotions or specials on behalf of companies with whom we have joint or cooperative marketing arrangements. You may take advantage of these promotions or specials by clicking on links on our site. You will be transferred to a different site which may not be owned or operated by Carnival where you may be required to provide personal information in order to participate in the promoted products or services. This privacy policy does not apply to those sites; please review the privacy policy posted on those sites. 

You may also choose how you would like to receive information from us, by mail, email or telephone. If you send us an email or request information we will retain your email address and use it to respond to your inquiry. We may also use your email address to provide you with details on upcoming events, cruises, packages and other information about Carnival or to provide you with information from companies with whom we have cooperative or joint marketing arrangements.  We may also use the information collected when you activate the mobile application to provide you with information about your cruise, activities, products or services that may be of interest to you through the application.

By providing personal information through this site you explicitly agree to our collection and use of that information as described in this Privacy Policy. You agree that we may use the personal information you provide to respond to your inquiries, process orders, contact you regarding customer service, let you know about products or services which may be of interest to you or to personalize our service to meet your needs or preferences. This may involve sharing certain information with our medical staff, affiliated companies or third parties, for instance, if you require a wheelchair or have dietary preferences. You also agree that we may share your personal information with our affiliated companies and third parties as described in this Privacy Policy. You further agree that the information you provide is current, accurate and that you will update it if there are any changes.

**Email Promotions**  
You may subscribe to our email promotions program by registering on one of our websites. By registering, you are securing your subscription to receive email promotions. You may unsubscribe or change your email address for email promotions at any time by following the instructions mentioned prominently within each email promotion.

**Sweepstakes**  
From time to time we may offer promotions, contests or sweepstakes on our site. If you choose to participate we will collect information including your name, address, age, telephone number and email address. We may also request other information some of which may be optional. We use the information you provide for purposes of conducting the promotion and for other purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Promotions may be sponsored by Carnival alone or with another sponsor or by a third party. Information you provide may be shared with the sponsor or third parties in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You must be over the age of 18 to participate in any promotion or sweepstakes. When you participate in a promotion you are subject to the Official Rules governing that promotion which will be posted on the site.

**Child Privacy**  
The website is not targeted at, nor do we knowingly collect personal data from, children under the age of 13. If we have reason to believe that information is being provided by a person under the age of 13 we will not collect the information.  Parents are required to register any child under the age of 13 who will have access to the mobile application.

**Your Access to Your Information**  
You are responsible for the accuracy and completeness of all information you provide to us. You may, at any time, access and make changes or corrections to your Profile Information or preferences simply by visiting the My Profile, My Cruise Manager or Online Check-in pages of the website and providing your Login Information. You may also direct us to change your information by email or telephone at the address provided below. You can direct us to remove your email address from our mailing list simply by following the instructions on any email you receive. We will act on your instructions promptly, but making changes may take two weeks or more to become effective.

**Disclosing Information to Third Parties**  
We do not sell our customers' information to third parties but we may share your information with our affiliated companies or with third parties. We may disclose your Profile and other information to those individuals linked to the same My Cruise Manager account.  We will reveal personal information to unaffiliated third parties only if: (1) you request or authorize it; (2) the information is provided to help complete a transaction for you; (3) the information is provided to comply with the law, applicable regulations, governmental and quasi-governmental requests, court orders or subpoenas, to enforce our Legal Notices or other agreements, or to protect our rights, property or safety or the rights, property or safety of our users or others (e.g., to a consumer reporting agency for fraud protection etc.); (4) the disclosure is done as part of a purchase, transfer or sale of services or assets (e.g., in the event that substantially all of our assets are acquired by another party, customer information may be one of the transferred assets); (5) the information is provided to our agents, outside vendors or service providers to perform functions on our behalf (e.g., analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing customer service, processing orders, sending emails about our products or services, etc.) or with whom we may have cooperative or joint marketing arrangements; (6) the information is shared with third parties for their marketing use, or (7) to others as described in this Privacy Policy. We may also gather aggregated data about you and disclose such aggregated (but not personally identifiable) information to third parties for promotional or other purposes.

**Affiliate Marketing Opt Out  
**Federal law gives you the right to limit some but not all marketing from Carnival. Federal law also requires us to give you this notice to tell you about your choice to limit marketing from Carnival. 

 You may limit our affiliates, including our sister cruise lines in the Carnival Corporation, from marketing their products or services to you based on personal information Carnival provides them. This information includes your name, your address, and your cruising history.

 Your choice to limit marketing offers will apply for 5 years from when you tell us your choice. Once that period expires, you may receive a renewal notice which will allow you to limit marketing offers for another 5 years. If you have already made a choice to limit marketing offers from us, you do not need to act again until you receive the renewal notice. To limit affiliate marketing offers, please email: [privacypolicy@carnival.com](mailto:privacypolicy@carnival.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or contact us toll free at 1-888-CARNIVAL. 

**Your California Privacy Rights**  
Carnival may disclose your personal information to our affiliates or other third parties for their use in the marketing of their products or services (as opposed to Carnival products or services) to you unless you tell us not to. In order to opt out of such sharing or for further information, please email: [privacypolicy@carnival.com](mailto:privacypolicy@carnival.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy) or contact us toll free at 1-888-CARNIVAL.  
****

**Transportation Security Administration Secure Flight Notice**

The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) requires you to provide your full name, date of birth and gender for the purpose of watch list screening under the authority of 49 U.S.C. section 114, the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 and 49 C.F.R. parts 1540 and 1560 for all commercial air travel within, into or out of the United States which is booked on or after August 15, 2009. 

 You may also provide your Redress Number, if available. If you book commercial air travel within, into or out of the United States in conjunction with your voyage we will request this information from you and forward it to the TSA as required by law. Failure to provide your full name, date of birth, and gender may result in denial of transport or denial of authority to enter the boarding area. 

 TSA may share information you provide with law enforcement or intelligence agencies or others under its published system of records notice. For more on TSA privacy policies or to review the system of records notice and the privacy impact assessment, please see the TSA Web site at [www.tsa.gov](http://www.tsa.gov/).

**Security Procedures to Protect Information  
**Security of personal information is extremely important to us. Carnival employs security measures consistent with standard industry practice to prevent unauthorized access to your personal information collected on and used by Carnival at this site. Our site uses SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) security technology to encrypt information you provide to us through the Site, but any information you provide us by email is unencrypted. SSL is an industry-standard protocol for encryption over the internet. Data transmission over the internet is never 100% secure. 

 While we take steps to protect your personal information and keep it secure, you also play a role in protecting your information. You can help to maintain the security of your online transactions by not sharing your login information, booking number or password with anyone. Carnival cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us or from our site, and therefore you use our site at your own risk.

**Inapplicability of Privacy Policies of any Linked Sites or Other Parties**  
Carnival's Sites may contain links to other sites such as our affiliates and third parties. This Privacy Policy only addresses Carnival's use and disclosure of your information collected on Sites displaying this Privacy Policy. While we try to link only to sites that share our standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of our affiliates or any other third parties or the content of linked sites, although we do encourage you to read the applicable privacy policies and terms and conditions of such parties or web sites.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
We will occasionally amend this Privacy Policy to reflect company and customer feedback and we reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. The use of your information is subject to the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use in effect at the time of use. The provisions contained in this Privacy Policy supersede all previous notices or policies regarding our privacy practices with respect to this site. We post the effective date of our Privacy Policy on our site. We encourage you to check our site frequently to see the current Privacy Policy to be informed of how Carnival is committed to protecting your information and providing you with improved content on our website in order to enhance your online cruise planning experience. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy we will post the revised Privacy Policy and the revised effective date on this site.

**Your Comments are Appreciated**  
If you have any questions, comments or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy, you can contact us via telephone at **1-888-CARNIVAL** , or email: [privacypolicy@carnival.com](mailto:privacypolicy@carnival.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy). If you have questions, comments or complaints not related to the Privacy Policy (e.g. reservations, cruise experience, marketing material, etc.), you can check the Customer Service area of this website. This site is owned and operated by Carnival Cruise Lines, a division of Carnival Corporation, which controls any information submitted through this site.

Effective Date: 2015 © Carnival Corporation, All rights reserved.
